realmadridshop.com 2008-12-17

# The Official Real Madrid Store

This document explains our policy regarding any personal information you might supply to us when you visit this site. Our goal is to protect your information.

Please note that this web site contains links to other websites which are provided for your convenience. We are only responsible for the privacy practices and security of this site. We recommend that you check the privacy and security policies and procedures of each and every other website that you visit.

**Data Responsibility**

Kitbag

The data that you give us as well as the data that you’ve facilitated in your purchase o orders are given to Kitbag, who will be responsible for your data maintenance.

Loyalty Real Madrid, C.F.

In addition, this store belongs to Real Madrid’s official stores and for that reason, all the purchases and personal data that you do in this store as well as all the ones you do at any other official store under Real Madrid’s C.F. brand, will be store in a file, which Real Madrid C.F. will be responsible. Your credit card details – or any details for payment – won’t be included on this file. The Real Madrid’s personal data file purpose is to globally administrate all the Real Madrid official stores so all the customers that have registered in any of the shops can have access to the information or access other stores –providing that the functionality is active -. This service also informs you of any Real Madrid offers or products from its sponsors or third parties indicated. Communication can be via mail or email, text messages or similar system and clients amongst all shops can receive, as a reward for your loyalty, opt ins in draws, competitions, discounts or direct prizes. Loyalty actions as well as prizes, discounts or draws will be informed ti the users by the club, who reserves the right to update them or improve them in order to include new advantages.

**Consent**

By registering or placing an order on the Kitbag website, you indicate your consent to us and our commercial partners collecting and using your personal information in accordance with the terms set out in this policy. If you do not agree to these terms, please do not register or place an order on this site. Details of our commercial partners are set out below.

**Collection of Personal Information**

When you engage in certain activities on this site, such as registering, ordering products, or entering contests, Kitbag may ask you to provide certain information about yourself by filling out and submitting an online form. It is completely optional for you to engage in these activities. If you elect to engage in these activities, however, Kitbag may require that you provide us with personal information, such as your name, mailing address, e-mail address, telephone number and other personal identifying information. When ordering products on the site, you may be asked to provide a credit or debit card number.

We may supplement the information that you provide with other information that we obtain from our dealings with you or which we receive from other organisations, for example, our commercial partners.

**How will we use your information**

When you submit personal information to Kitbag you understand and agree that Kitbag and its subsidiaries, affiliates and trusted vendors may record, transfer, store, and process your customer profile in any of the countries in which Kitbag and its affiliates maintain offices, including without limitation, the United Kingdom. All personal information submitted will be protected by us in accordance with current data protection legislation and this privacy policy. Kitbag collects this information in order to record and support your participation in the activities you select. If you order a product, for example, the information is used to mail to you the items ordered and to provide you with any benefits that may be made available to registered users. If you enter a contest, information is collected to qualify the entry and contact you regarding the contest or prize awards. Kitbag also uses information that you provide:

  1. as part of our effort to keep you informed via mail, email, phone or fax about special offers, and other Kitbag products and services
  2. for record keeping purposes
  3. to improve the quality of our service
  4. for market research
  5. to track activity on our website
  6. to understand your preferences so that we can improve the products or services we offer
  7. In Real Madrid's case, the purpose to collect information is the management of the loyalty action and in the case it was active, the access to the remaining Real Madrid C.F. official shops, as has been previously decribed.

Kitbag recognises and appreciates the importance of responsible use of this information. If you do not want the information you provide to Kitbag to be used to inform you of other products and special offers from Kitbag, and you indicate this preference when you provide the information to us, we will honour your preference. In addition, Kitbag may selectively provide certain information to other companies or organisations that have products or services we think may interest you. If you do not want the information you provide to Kitbag to be shared with other companies, and you indicate this preference when you provide the information to us, we will honour your preference.

Your personal information is password-protected to prevent unauthorised access to it. We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone.

**Disclosure of your information**

In addition to the disclosure to the Club’s commercial partners, we may need to appoint other organisations to carry out some of the processing activities on our behalf in order to provide our products and services to you. These will include, for example, delivery organisations and mailing houses. In these circumstances, we will ensure that your information is properly protected and that it is only used in accordance with this policy.

Finally, if our business enters into a joint venture with or is sold to or merged with another business entity, your information may be disclosed to our new partners or owners.

Unless required to do so by law, we will not otherwise share, sell or distribute any of the information you provide to us without your consent.

**Offers and opportunities**

The Online Store and the Club teams up with a selection of carefully chosen commercial partners such as:

\- Adidas

\- Audi

\- Babybel

\- Banesto

\- BWIN

\- Metro News S.L.

\- Coca Cola

\- Comunidad de Madrid

\- Grupo Mahon San Miguel

\- Planeta E-Commerce Network S.L.

\- Sánchez Romero

\- Sanitas

\- Solan de Cabras

\- UnileverM

\- Vueling

The Club’s commercial partner programme is designed to support the Club and also to bring customers, fans and website users a diverse range of opportunities and offers (including financial services offers) at competitive prices. We and/or the Club and/or these commercial partners would like to contact you with details of offers in a number of ways, including post, telephone, text/picture/video message, digital television, fax or by email. If you express an interest in an offer from on of our commercial partners, that partner may let us know. This enables us to take your views and interests into account when choosing our commercial partners and developing the programme.

If you do not wish for your personal information to be passed on in this way, please contact as specified below

**What to do if you do not want to receive details of offers**

Please be assured, you are under no obligation to buy anything, however, if you prefer not to be contacted either by us or any of our commercial partners, you can opt out of receiving these details by writing to us by mail or email (see the section "How to contact us" below). You can change your mind at any time by contacting us by any of the methods shown below or by following the instructions set out with each offer you receive.

Please note, if you do opt out of receiving information, we and/or our commercial partners will be unable to keep you informed of new services, products, events or special offers that may interest you and our ability to inform you of ticketing opportunities may be affected.

**Use of your information outside the European Union**

Some of the organisations to which we may disclose your personal information are situated outside of the European Union. In order to provide you with the products and services you require, we may need to transfer your personal information to these countries some of which do not have laws that protect privacy rights as extensively as in the United Kingdom. If we do transfer your personal information to other territories, we will take proper steps to ensure that your information is properly protected.

**Use of Cookies**

When you visit Kitbag, you can surf the site anonymously and access important information without revealing your identity. However, in order to provide better service, we may use "cookies" to track your visit, which make it easier for you to log on during future visits. A cookie is a small piece of information that the Web site stores on your Web browser and can later retrieve. We use cookies for a number of administrative purposes, such as recording your log in status so you do not have to log in to the site at every visit (unless you wish to).

The cookie cannot be read by a Web site other than the one that sent the cookie.

While Kitbag uses cookies to track your visit, most cookies last only through a single session or visit. Similarly this information does not identify you personally and you remain anonymous unless you have otherwise provided Kitbag with personal information. Please note that it is possible to set up your Web browser to inform you when you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether or not to accept it.

For further information on cookies and how to switch them off see www.allaboutcookies.org

**Data Protection**

Kitbag Ltd is registered in accordance with United Kingdom Data Protection Legislation and will hold and use your personal data strictly in accordance with UK data protection legislation.

**How does Kitbag protect visitor information?**

Kitbag has a committed Security Policy. Kitbag will retain copies of the information provided when you register on the website, order any products from the site and enter into any competitions. Kitbag implements a number of sophisticated security measures to ensure the safety of any personal information provided. The information is contained on a secure server, which is accessible only by a limited number of employees who have authorised access rights to such information. All sensitive and credit card information supplied by any visitor to store.manutd.com is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology. SSL is commonly-used for managing the security of message transmission on the Internet through public-and-private key encryption and a digital certificate that establishes your credentials when doing Internet business or other on-line transactions. This certificate is issued by a certification authority, in our case Verisign. To see the certificate for this site click Verisign here. When you are asked to enter any personal details or credit card information the web site will be secure. This is easily identifiable by an icon in the bottom of the browser window resembling an unbroken key or a closed lock. SSL ensures that the information being sent is secure. Your card number will be encrypted and replaced by a unique transaction reference number. Kitbag uses online bank secure servers provided by DataCash and does not hold any customer card details on any Kitbag server at any time. To remove any name and address details please see remove details section in the Kitbags help menu.

In addition, we have security procedures in place to protect our paper based systems and computerised databases from access by unauthorised persons and against unlawful processing, accidental loss, destruction and damage, and only allow access to them when it is absolutely necessary to do so, and then under strict guidelines as to what use may be made of the personal information contained within them.

**

Changes to this privacy policy

**

We aim to meet high standards and our policies and procedures are, therefore, constantly under review. From time to time we may change our security and privacy policies. Accordingly we recommend that you check this page periodically in order to review our current policies.

**Updating and correcting information**

You may correct your personal information by emailing us at [customerservices@realmadridshop.com](mailto:customerservices@realmadridshop.com) or by changing your profile on our website. Please include your name, address and/or email address when you contact us as this helps us to ensure that we accept amendments only from the correct person. We encourage you to promptly update your personal information if it changes.

**Your rights to access your personal information**

You have the right to see a copy of the personal information that we hold about you, and you may ask us to make any necessary changes to ensure that this information is accurate and kept up to date. We may charge a small fee towards the cost of administering any request you make. The current fee is £10.00. You may ask us to make any necessary changes to your personal information to ensure it is accurate and up-to-date.
